# Lei Zhong



## **Biography**

I am a second-year MPhil candidate in the College of Computer Science, Nankai University. Prior to that, I earned a B.Eng degree at Southwest University in China, under the supervision of Dr. Jianfeng Li and Prof. Tong Chen. My research interests mainly lie in computer vision and deep learning with an emphasis on computational photography and character animation.

## **EDUCATION**

Nankai University Sep 2020

MPhil in Computer Science Tianjin, CN

Southwest University Sep 2016

B.E. in Electronic Information Engineering Chongqing, CN

GPA:3.78 (Top 5% of Major)

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

### Aesthetics guided image composition

Sep 2020 - Present

In this study, an image cropping algorithm based on image content and aesthetics is proposed, and the experimental results have significant advantages in quantitative evaluation and subjective evaluation.

- Proposed a novel algorithm that can adjust the image field of view is proposed, which expands the application range of existing image cropping algorithms.
- · Proposed a method to balance image aesthetics and image quality.
- Published a paper at ACM TOG (SIGGRAPH Asia 2021).

### Face expression recognition based on graph structure

Jan 2018 - Sep 2019

- Proposed novel graph-based facial expression feature representation methods to improve the recognition of facial expression.
- Evaluated the proposed methods on CASME, CK+, and MMI datasets, and achieved significantly improved recognition accuracy.
- Published papers at FG2019 and ICANN2020.

### **KEY PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. **Lei Zhong**, Feng-Heng Li, HaoZhi Huang, Yong Zhang, Shap-Ping Lu, "Aesthetic-guided Outward Image Cropping" In ACM Transactions on Graphics (SIGGRAPH Aisa 2021).
- 2. **Lei Zhong**, Changmin Bai, Jianfeng Li. "Generating full-view face images from a single-view image". In International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN2021).
- 3. **Lei Zhong,** Changmin Bai, Jianfeng Li, Tong Chen, Shigang Li. "Facial Expression Recognition Method Based on a Part-Based Temporal Convolutional Network with a Graph-Structured Representation" In International Conference on Artificial Neural Networks (ICANN 2020).
- 4. **Lei Zhong**, Changmin Bai, Jianfeng Li, Tong Chen, Shigang Li, Yiguang Liu. "A Graph-Structured Representation with BRNN for Static-based Facial Expression Recognition" In IEEE International Conference on Automatic Face & Gesture Recognition (FG 2019).

#### **INTERNSHIPS**

Tencent Al Lab Jul 2021 - Jan 2022

Research Intern ShenZhen, CN

Character Animation and Motion Synthesis.